you
I welcome back to the wheel of life home
retreat hola bienvenidos a new a vowel
retiro in casa de la rua da de la vida
today my translators Allison Cho thank
you for coming
ome TRADOC Dora is Alice mojo gracias
por venir session 14 is called contact
with the outside la session Couture
sasayama contacto con el exterior
and the image were using is bunch of
kids looking out a window with a
telescope la meheeco Somozas un grupo de
niñas mirando por una ventana con on
telescope you
and this kind of represents all the
parts of your mind
yes tone cierto modo representatives las
partes de tu mente making their first
contact with the outside haciendo su
primer contacto con el exterior so where
have we come in the wheel of life so far
entonces vamos a god oh la la vida
stably number one tenemos Alice LeBeau
numero uno you misunderstand your
husband you say entiendes in
correctamente to spa so he says yo no se
nada el Negrito then step number 2
entonces paso no matter though you make
karma cause you don't understand him
Isis karma David okay no no entiendes
I'm not stupid you're stupid if he says
Jonas I used to be that tourist that
commerce impressed onto the mind and
this is a karma sim Pramila meant a you
carry that mind to your next life
J was a cement a at approx antis to
internal ooh taro it enters the blood in
and the semen in Tibetan it's called the
blood and enter less angry NL salmon in
Tibetan ooyama la sangre and salmon and
I've been calling it menstrual blood and
semen yo lo estoy yo - angry menstrual
is salmon
but of course we understand now that we
have microscopes but a por supuesto a
que tenemos microscope use and ten demos
that it's really the semen and the seed
of the mother which is in the play okay
s realmente l cemani las semillas de la
madre que stainless angry okay then the
mind enters that such consist of
substances entonces la mente entra en
estas estancia SS substances at link
number 3 which is called consciousness
and it's the monkey and trained in illis
level numero tres the monkey entering no
es la beau numero tres que se Amado
conciencia pero es el mano entrando la
Lu Tarot
now and then we talked already about
link number 4 hemos hablado Alice LeBeau
numero Quatro which is basically your
body in your mind developing inside the
womb chaos was he commented to cuerpo tu
mente the sorrow Yan dose adentro the
new taro and now we rinsed link number 5
yeah don't forget why we are learning
all of these links estamos aprendiendo
ptosis to see slobbiness these are the
steps in the process that trigger each
other
it's a son los pasos en el proceso en el
que si active and n Tracy and their
Harry get in trouble it kimonos meta
Mohsen problemas if you're in this wheel
si esta sinister whether you are having
trouble in your life it's justin in the
problemas en tu vida
baby that's amore des and the goal of
learning all these links yellow que tipo
de aprender todos estos isla bonus is to
learn how to stop them
it's aprender como de tener knows it
doesn't mean we disappear no significa
que they separate if not doesn't mean
you disappear no significa que the
separation it just means your life
changes so no significa que tu vida
cumbia into a perfect life where you
cannot die you cannot get old I will not
be the perfect ad on the new
post-meridian no puedo Samba hey sir
ok so we reached link number 5 bien de
Gama solace lava novorossiya in tibet
it's called another chi chi n TV tano is
napa tha and what it means is the doors
of sense
yo lo que significa s las puertas de los
Santino's let's go to the text vamos el
texto
like a cheeky tenderness so what is the
link that we call number 5 quanis Ellis
Levante llamamos numero Cinco and these
are the organs of sense yes so so loss
or Ginoza no Santino's macness okey kg
to japanese soon so this link goes from
the time that your instruments for
experience in the world are developing
like your eye a second estes la bomba
des el momento en que tous instrumentos
para experimenter el mundo sustained the
cerulean DoCoMo to aho it was like the
heart suture as he case kamasutra el
corazon McManaman mhm enemy Masumi okay
yeah go die by Lajo ears widows no
daddy's done lengua skin PA and it is
postman take your mind is also one of
your sense organs a secret to men taste
ambien or ginosaji he says six six sense
organs here
I see kale this is a sort of a no
sensorially sake so once you have an eye
a Sakura is cattiness you start to
experience the outside world what is a
bizarre experiment our almond exterior
that experience begins when the eye
meets the object meets the mind behind
the eye those three things experiencia
commence a cuando lo ho se encuentran
con el objeto que se encuentra con la
mente detrás de lo ho es a stress causes
so so far we aren't yet able to
experience the details of the object s
tyrannosaurs capacitor on the experiment
our loss it is a look at them we do have
an eye we do have a nose we do have a
ear si tenemos una Hoshi tenemos una
Nardi empty houses but a song como
classes Macias and that's the image in
the link here yes s lima Henan and vinca
lucky nobody's looking out the window
yet Nadia Samara no por La Ventana
todavía the first dose
since faculties have to develop a secret
primero SS facultad SLO Santino's penis
look out you little push me that extends
a little you give our money member
company a person it is stated that even
from the time that your consciousness
enters that messy blood and semen
establecido conclusive does el momento
que tu conciencia enter a miserable tour
de sangre si means you don't yet have I
I want no tiene sauce
but traditionally they say better
traditional mentally thinking that first
few minutes inside your mom there's a
los primeros minutos entrada tu madre
when your mind enters those liquids
cuando tu mente and Trini so slick Eidos
you do have the sense power of thought
tienes sa peau de el sentido el
pensamiento
and you do have a kind of skin it's just
come right now se tiene un especial de
piel a solo como esto ahora mismo ticket
double come on my knees I mean tsuki
tender than kgk tender cheek chapter 2
now there's a kind of special kind of
birth in Buddhist origin tip especially
nacimiento en el Buddhism oh and certain
special people are just born in a second
complete inside a lotus for example done
this year cos personas especiales
Nazanin un segundo completo centro de un
lot o por ejemplo like this thing a
silly girl in one second till I put in
their hope prison luego no segundos como
pop is on a persona completely so those
are in the lower two realms desire realm
and formula and assess an illusory no
Severus in el drano well they say they
say that the name and form the two parts
of body and mind in the single nombre la
forma las partes del cuerpo maintain a
lute arrow the two parts body and mind
inside one las dos part a square Pimenta
dentro de Loup Tarot and this link which
is number five number five
yes this la boca says no Cinco is La one
numero Cinco tutorial is like
miraculously seen SS Milagro cemente say
you so said in and mismo tiempo so
there's no distinction that the body in
the womb and the body outside of a
second a decision and turn cuerpo and
eleuterio el cuerpo for Adela Tarot so
Melanie attended on educating attended
some less certain cases such a night and
um me and when you're talking about a
person who's being born into the
formless realm when this s hablando de
una persona que estas en turn already no
sin for me they don't have the name of
name and form because the name I'm sorry
I'm sorry
they don't have the form part they just
had the name for just a mental note en
la parte de la forma sólo tiene la parte
del nombre sólo la parte mental ugh a
contender and they have the sense organ
of the thought tienen el organ oh so
sorry al del Prince I mean you don't
have the others
the other five pero tienen los otros law
so true Cinco no so for the Soyuz
Reynolds that finishes his presentation
of the sentence it's a 3-2 presentation
the see the new single okay okay link
number 6 we've reached a moussaka
solderless level numero seis which is
called contact here's your mother
contact and here's the description it's
not very long
by the way the image is a man touching a
woman ya Castella description knows
malaria for certain mechanism number two
condone a mohair and this link does not
refer to two sexes or something like the
rest even cool oh no sorry funeral sex
Oh Elvis it's a different kind of
contact
it's one people different icon so the
painting is just a metaphor
I see Kayla pintura solo in a metaphor
okay so duper a bunny link number 6
LS level numero seis it's called contact
say I'm a contact oh so now the sense
organs have formed a CEO or a loss organ
Assessor really say formado and three
things make three things make contact it
riscos assassin contact oh okay here's
your eye for example I guess that blue
power el poder de lo ho then here's a
red apple and this is a key elements an
Aloha and then here's the awareness of
the red apple se que aqui esta la
conciencia de la montaña Willa when the
iris is the red I see cuando la home el
Rojo and the mind is aware of the red
element associated and Rojo when these
teeth make contact
cuando su stress as in contact oh we
call it contact oh yeah my most contact
oh okay so here in the text it says it
was a secular text to this you Womble
namsom take the object the red apple
Olivia toe lemons and Roja descent para
TI el poder de los sonidos and the
awareness of red fo y la conciencia
elements an Aloha
they meet each other cincuenta no not
Rome
yes Osama contact oh okay after contact
disposal contact oh then
the house we stay by the way during
contact sorry por cierto durante el
contacto / done I'm gonna contents
change that that contact up to the time
that you are able to distinguish si
contacto esta el momento que puede si
Senor lo o this is something nice this
is not something nice Oh estos algo
bonito ESO no es algo bonito that period
of contact has been made it's a period
of the contact oh say I hate you but
you're not feeling anything yet
better nurse's in theand another wound
that that link is called number six it's
this Lagoon so yeah man we replace
contact okay now that causes number
seven our ISO causa in the medicine over
seven which is called Dumbo is
lammeter's hit a Cosima
Duma significant love on American soil
means feelings sir was significant
sentimientos here's the definition I
guess that on the Feeny Dumba Suwannee
River Kinkaid saw rotated Tonya some
chilly cavity because the mind and the
center and the object make contact Deba
que la mente el poder de los sonidos yo
hetoh hacen contacto
then you can start to say oh I like
apples or I'm allergic to apples until
Cespedes M percerin decir oh my gooosh
las montañas oh so eller he can happier
you can feel fun a person till the
Felisa positive direction
that's called feeling yes asahiyama
sentiment that traditional picture like
mecca traditional it's a very terrible
kind of feeling that the man has an
arrow in his eyes a scintilla
sentimental terribly el hombre en una
flow channel oh ho and it's just an
extreme example yes alone ejemplos
extreme OD sentiment oh of course it's
feeling intense pain
por supuesto Cynthia nun de Lorean 10 so
now what kinds of feeling are there
Erica tip of the sentimientos existence
they means a nice feeling their
significant sentimiento missin him Duke
significa donat chun-yan means I don't
feel good I don't feel bad hang on
significant oh my siento bien no massive
neutral feeling so long sentimental
neutral silly chaotic as soon as there's
contact tan pronto como el contacto one
of those feelings will come up you know
this was sentimental Sahira now usually
we would say how are you feeling
normally Montevideo Mo's come out the
CNAs I don't know in English well I'm
not feeling anything right now an
English ASIMO's or nurse - Cynthia nor
neither am i I don't enjoy this thing
notice that cause I don't dislike this
thing no me gusta staccato solamente
como que no siento nada en este momento
but in Buddhist philosophy para la
philosophy emily's you're always feeling
cm priestess entiendo algo the feeling
might be neutral a centimeter placer
neutral but you are still having a
feeling better I own a city and so
sentimental
once there's contact with the outside
world una vez que contacto con el mundo
stereo or even hearing your own thoughts
inclusive which artists produce pens I
mean you just start to feel something in
pieces isn't here anymore and one of the
kinds of suffering in this world you
know velocity poses so freemen tone is
the moon is that you cannot turn those
feelings on
es que no puedo Pagar a so sentiment
owes when I first started to teach him
in New York maybe 35 years ago
cuando common sense in Genoa York etc
enticing Kuan Yew's I used to interview
every slowly and revista de todos los
estudiantes and I didn't have time I
used to interview them because I was
working full-time at the time in
business
I know Taniya tiempo solely on Travis
Carlos por que trabaja de tiempo
completo en el negocio de los de
amante's
so I would meet people at lunch time I
see Cameroonian con la gente I
distinctly remember meeting this person
you know Clemente ever miss owner
when La Quinta Avenida and we had lunch
together
il Moro Santos juntos and ice I said you
know I said what do you do for a living
yo-dee-hey Akita teddicus and he said I
steal things I'm a robber because I got
nervous I I'm like holding my phone that
happens in every or so
oh and series yeah I still see your room
por las Casas de la gente I'm surprising
I said it's a footprint do we hey porque
no I'm heroin addict so unique Toledo
inner what I need money horse we
addicted I mean I'm injector Irina
necesito dinero then I've take this this
guy cannot come into our school he was
do everything interns has been say it
was the chicken apple internal stress
querulous arawa Rotolo
but I something came in my mind but I
will be no me meant a I said I never
tried heroin d hey joko prevail arrow in
I said why why do you do that why did
you take heroin let me hear pork ssso
porque consume I said I want to stop
feeling thing in the hockey row the
Hardison fear causes I don't care good
feeling and bad feeling I don't want
anything no me importa see some point
sentimiento on mal sentimiento no quiero
ninguna Santino I don't want to kill
myself
look you dose we see that me cuz I'm
afraid I don't know what will happen
porque tengo miedo no se que pasar ax
but I'm tired of feeling things first I
can't settle this until Casas it's too
much for me
it's a Masiello para me just after I
take the heroin whose - this was a
consummate arena that for our two hours
I don't feel anything
durante horas so we have to say
according to this he is feeling things
really that look at the rooms caddesi
record o con esto es que estas entiendo
kosis it's a so sentimental neutral and
we are always feeling siempre hemos
entiendo
and that's one of the sufferings of the
Wheel of Life yes a soonerlater so free
mentor sell rather than la vida
you cannot stop feeling no puede dejar
de Cynthia my little brother committed
suicide me hermano pequeno sister sido
and he was very intelligent yellow more
intelligent a and he
strong and handsome 20 years old Arif
we're tape Wahpeton every 10 News he
said I just want to stop the feeling
parody hose to look you know they have
the same thing he says to see though now
unfortunately or fortunately we love my
Labradoodle Amina even if you shoot
brain which he did inclusive Solaris
Paris are cerebro la cual ELISA
you cannot stop the life - no puede
tener la vida the mine is still alive
lament to see habiba the mind will not
die lament a no Marita
and the mind will go to another place
Elementary Otto Gahr and it will go to
another circles and you will have
feeling it won't stop for one second a
pasar por otro Circulo a tendrá
sentiment owes no say death and renewal
so so we need to find another way out of
the wheel hace que necesitamos
uncontroverted forma de salir de marina
and that's weird why we are studying the
will be por ESO stenosis to the under a
broiler so we'll see you again in
session 15 se que nos vemos on web or
less this your key in say we're gonna
find out but most everywhere so after
you plant the same I see continue to
grow to start growing casa que las a
medium PSA crecer start
and we're gonna talk about that in
section 15 iva-mos hablar de so unless
you can say a Stanton says
you